有时，最微小的细节，也足以颠覆一切
Sometimes, the smallest detail can change everything.
犯罪现场，或残酷，或丑陋，或恐怖
A crime scene can be brutal, ugly, horrifying.
可一旦留下某种怪诞而费解之物，便会衍变为传奇
But when something strange and unexplained is left behind, it crosses into legend.
这正是2013年杭州发生的故事，
And that's what happened in Hangzhou in 2013.
一桩本该直截了当的谋杀案
A murder case that should have been straightforward
却因三件寻常之物，而在网络上声名狼藉
became infamous online because of three simple objects.
几张扑克牌
A handful of playing cards.
这几张牌，仿佛是来自逝者或凶手的讯息
Cards that seem like a message from the dead or the killer.
2013年3月15日清晨
On the morning of March 15th, 2013,
杭州的一位年迈拾荒者，正沿世纪大道捡拾废品
an elderly scavenger in Hangzhou was collecting scraps along the Century Avenue.
在良熟村附近，他发现了一个被遗弃的大纸箱
He spotted a large cardboard box abandoned near Liangshu Village.
起初并无异常
At first, it was nothing unusual
直到他瞥见箱底渗出的血迹
until he noticed blood seeping through the bottom.
惊恐之下，他唤来一名环卫工
Frightened, he called over a street cleaner.
二人合力撬开纸箱
Together, they pried it open.
里面竟是一具尸体
Inside was a human body.
警方迅速抵达现场
The police arrived quickly.
尸身属于一位年轻女子，伤痕累累
And the body belonged to a young woman. Badly scarred.
确认已死亡数日，时间大约在3月10日前后
And was confirmed dead for several days. Sometime around March 10th.
这显然是一起凶杀案
And it was very clearly a homicide.
她曾遭殴打、捆绑，并被塞入箱中
She had been beaten, bound, and stuffed into the box.
但勘察人员还发现了别的东西
But investigators found something else.
三张扑克牌与尸身共存箱内
Three playing cards inside with their body.
黑桃五、方块J和黑桃K
The Five of Spades. The Jack of Diamonds. And the King of Spades.
这几张牌与现场的残暴景象格格不入
And the cards didn't match the brutality of the scene.
它们看起来像是被刻意放置于此
They looked like they were placed there on purpose.
警方核查了本地的失踪人口记录，一无所获
Police checked local missing persons. And nothing matched.
于是他们将受害者的衣物、纹身以及那三张牌的照片公之于网
So they released photos of the victim's clothing, her tattoos, and the three cards online.
案件就此在中国各大论坛上引爆
And that's when the case exploded across Chinese forums.
网民们剖析着每一条线索
Netizens dissected every clue.
有人说，KJ5意为“快救我”
Some said, KJ5 meant help me.
有人则认为它是一个车牌号
Others thought it was a license plate code.
甚至有人推测，这几个字母对应着凶手的姓名缩写
And some even speculated the letters matched the killer's initials.
这几张牌，将一桩谋杀案变成了一桩充满密码、象征、近乎电影情节的悬案
The cards turned to murder into a mystery that felt coded, symbolic, and almost cinematic.
但对警方而言，问题更为纯粹
But for the detectives, the problem was simpler.
他们甚至连她是谁都不知道
They didn't know who she even was.
然而网民们却不肯罢休
But people online refused to let it go.
人们追查到售卖她衣物的店铺
People tracked down the shops that sold her clothing.
纹身爱好者在档案中搜寻相同的设计
Tattoo enthusiasts searched archives for the same design.
还有人将她的照片与失踪人员通告逐一比对
And others compared her photo to the missing person notices.
尽管大部分努力都徒劳无功
And while most of it led to nowhere,
却让此案持续停留在公众的视野里
it kept the case alive in the public eye.
终于，一条线索改变了一切
And finally, one tip changed everything.
近一个月后的4月10日
On April 10th, nearly a month later,
一位杭州市民报告称，他曾见过这名女子
a Hangzhou resident reported that they had seen a woman before,
她住在余杭的联盟社区
living in the Lianmeng community, in Yuhang.
警方随即走访了那个社区
Police canvassed the neighborhood.
一家超市老板忆起一件怪事
A supermarket owner remembered something odd.
一个身材微胖、身高约170厘米的男子
A slightly overweight man, about 170 centimeters tall,
买了两卷厚实的透明胶带
buying two rolls of thick, transparent tape.
与捆绑尸身所用的胶带是同一类型
The same kind of tape used to bind a body.
监控录像确认了他的身份
And security cameras confirmed his identity.
他姓何
His name was He.
邻居们说，受害者是他的女友
And neighbors said the victim was his girlfriend.
当警方在一家服装厂找到他时，他供认不讳
When police tracked him down at the garment factory, he confessed.
他和后来被确认为“程某”的受害者
He and the victim later identified as Cheng
自2012年12月开始交往
had been dating since December of 2012.
但他嫉妒心极强
But he was very jealous.
他看到她在网上与另一名男子聊天
He saw her chatting with another man online.
便要求她停止
He demanded her to stop.
而当她拒绝时，他的怒火被点燃了
And when she refused, his anger boiled over.
3月10日，他彻底失控
And on March 10th, he snapped.
他勒死了她，用胶带捆绑其尸身
He strangled her, taped her body,
将其塞入箱中，然后弃于路边
stuffed her into a box, and dumped it on the roadside.
当警方追问那些扑克牌时
And when the detectives pressed him on the cards,
他说他毫不知情
he said he had no idea.
他说在挣扎中，想必是撞倒了一个抽屉
He says that in the struggle, he must have knocked over a drawer.
那些牌应该是掉了出来，混进了箱子里
And the cards must have fallen out and gotten mixed into the box.
这是一个平淡无奇的解释
It's a very mundane explanation.
但在他坦白之时，互联网已将这几张牌塑造成神话
But by the time he confessed, the internet had already transformed the cards into myth.
将一桩简单的凶杀案
Turning a simple domestic killing
演变为中国现代“奇案”之一
into one of the eeriest modern cases in China.
而最终的真相是丑陋的
And in the end, the truth was ugly.
一桩因嫉妒引发的罪行
A crime of jealousy.
一个女人的生命被夺走
A woman's life taken.
她所信任之人亲自动手
By someone she trusted.
而离奇的是
And what's weird is,
人们所铭记的，不仅仅是罪行本身
what people remember isn't just the crime.
而是那些牌
It's the cards.
因为仅仅三张毫无意义的纸片
Because just three meaningless scraps of paper
却创造了一个比案件本身更长久的故事
created a story that lived far longer than the case itself.
梦境本应是无害的
潜意识转瞬即逝的碎片
但如果我说，梦能引导警方找到藏尸地点呢？
2008年，在吉林省的一个小镇上
这样的事情真实发生了
一名男子失踪了，随后人们发现了他带血的衣物
随后他的姐姐做了一个梦
一个准确告诉她去哪里寻找尸体的梦
故事还要从张永成此人说起
他是一位居住在长白山市的商贩
他为人友好，广受欢迎
靠买卖山货为生
2008年6月11日
在帮助他的邻居兼生意伙伴刘晓林整理完货物之后
他在晚十点左右穿着迷彩夹克离开了刘晓林家
从刘家到他家走路只要一分钟
但这条路他却再也没能走完
日子一天天过去，没有人再见过他
一周后，村里人发现了奇怪的东西：
被压在柴火堆下的一件迷彩衣
浸满了鲜血
警方确认这件衬衫属于张永成
奇怪的是，胸口处有一个圆形的洞
不是刀割，而是更血腥的痕迹
布料周围散落着几缕头发
调查人员立刻意识到这不是一场意外
而是一起谋杀
警方搜查整个村庄时
他们注意到了刘晓林家和张家之间的沙堆
成群的苍蝇在上面嗡嗡飞行
警员向下挖掘后
又发现了深色的污渍—血液
正渗入泥土中
邻居们还报告说，在张永成失踪的6月11日晚
曾听到沙堆附近传来巨响
很明显，这里发生过暴力事件
但警方却始终找不到张永成的尸体
正当调查人员束手无策时
张永成的姐姐张燕找到了警方
她说她做了一个梦
她弟弟在梦里跟她说了话
准确地描述了自己被埋葬的位置
往西，沿着铁路线，在铁轨的南边
警方当然不会相信这种超自然线索
但为了安慰这位悲伤的亲属
他们还是派出了一个小组前去调查
而他们的发现震惊了所有人
在铁路线旁一块被动过的土地上
离地表约两米深处
正是张永成的尸体
他身上有十三处刀伤，其中一刀刺穿了心脏
他正是在失踪的那天晚上被杀害的
梦的指示让案件调查产生了新的方向
警方甚至怀疑张燕本人是否涉案
毕竟
她怎么可能如此准确地知道埋尸地点呢？
但她只有1米56高，体型瘦弱
根本不可能挖出这么大一个墓穴
更别说如何搬动张永成两百多斤的尸体了
于是警方的注意力又回到了他身边的村民身上
事情真相很快便浮出水面
张永成和他的生意伙伴刘晓林有过一段恋情
但刘晓林已是有夫之妇，她的丈夫是铁路工人顾大海
而且在张永成之前，刘晓林还有另一个情夫
名叫韩志刚
这不仅仅是一起谋杀案
更是一张由痴迷和不忠交织而成的复杂关系网
起初，刘晓林的丈夫顾大海被警方列为嫌疑人
作为一名铁路工人，他对埋尸一带非常熟悉
因此极有可能将尸体埋在铁路沿线的是他
但证据并不吻合
顾大海坚称自己没有作案动机
甚至还说张永成是他的好铁子
随后另一个人物出现了——
刘晓林的前情人韩志刚
他占有欲强、嫉妒心重
对刘晓林移情别恋一事心怀怨恨
而就在张永成尸体被发现之后
韩志刚就“恰好”消失了
警方随即加紧了调查
调查发现，韩志刚在谋杀当晚
借了村民的一辆独轮车
声称需要搬运沙子
而当独轮车被送回时，已经被擦洗得一尘不染
经过进一步检测，警方发现了微量的血迹
也就是张永成的血
随后是最后一块拼图
在韩志刚家院子里的一个浴缸下面，藏着一个塑料袋
警方在袋中找到了两把仍沾有张永成血迹的刀
走投无路之下，韩志刚坦白了罪行
2008年6月11日
韩志刚撞见张永成离开了卢小林的家
一怒之下，他用刀袭击了张永成
随后发生了一场激烈的搏斗
张永成奋力反抗，衣服也随即撕破
但最终，他不敌韩志刚而身中13刀
倒在了沙堆边
韩志刚随后用独轮车将尸体运到铁路沿线
然后将他深埋入土中
就是纯粹出于嫉妒心而犯案，仅此而已
但这起案件之所以臭名昭著
是因为其中最令人发毛的细节
——揭示藏尸处的梦
张永成的姐姐
无论是出于巧合、直觉，还是某种无法解释的力量
她直接指出了藏尸之处
她的弟弟也终于得以安息
大多数谋杀案要么靠证据侦破，要么靠供词
但这起案件却是由一个梦侦破的
2014年 在那个神奇的山东招远市
In 2014, in Zhao Yun City, China,
一家麦当劳成为了被监控拍下的top5哈人犯罪现场之一
the McDonald's became the scene of one of the most disturbing crimes caught on surveillance.
这是一场发生在家庭、孩子和顾客面前的血腥谋杀
A murder carried out in front of families, children, and customers.
而凶手们 则相信自己正在对抗“恶灵”
All by a group who believed they were fighting evil spirits.
那是5月28日 一个五指不见伸手的夜晚
It was the evening of May 28th.
37岁的吴硕艳是在一位在附近一家服装店工作的销售员
Wu Zhao Yun, 37 years old, a salesperson who worked at a nearby clothing store.
已经下班的她在麦当劳等着家人们的到来
After work, she was waiting at a McDonald's for her family to arrive.
大约晚上9点 六个人走了进来 包括五名成年人和一个少年
Around 9 pm, a group of six people entered, a mix of adults, and even one teenager.
但他们不是来点餐的
But they weren't there to order food.
他们是来传教的
Instead, they started preaching to customers, telling them about their religious beliefs.
但这还没完
But it didn't just stop there.
他们还要所有人的手机号码 声称他们将来还会联系
It began demanding everyone's cell phone numbers, claiming they needed them to future contact.
而当吴数次拒绝他们时 他们就开始向她发起攻击
And when Wu refused, not once, but twice, they turned on her.
这群人喊道 她是个恶魔
The group shouted that she was an evil spirit.
然后他们就开始在餐厅里所有人的面前攻击她
And then, in front of the entire restaurant, they began attacking her.
他们使用的武器包括椅子、拖把和他们的脚
Chairs, mops, and their feet.
这些动作毫不留情
The beating was merciless.
而任何试图干预的人则都受到了同样的威胁
And anyone who tried to intervene was threatened with the same fate.
而监控拍下了这一切
and the CCTV cameras recorded everything.
顾客们惊恐地不断后退 而吴则在众目睽睽之下被殴打致死
Customers backed away in fear as Wu was beaten to death and in full public view.
当警察到达时 他们逮捕了六名袭击者
When police finally arrived, they arrested all six attackers.
中国政府的通报称 凶手是“全能神”教会的成员
The Chinese government quickly reported that the killers were members of the Eastern Lightning cult.
这是一个备受争议的、根据基督教瞎编的教派
It's a controversial Christian-inspired sect.
该教派成立于1990年代 长期以来被国家列入邪教的清单
Found in the 1990s, which has been long accused by the state of being a dangerous cult.
全能神教会 是一个受基督教启发的团体 于1990年代在中国成立
Eastern Lightning, or the Church of Almighty God, is a Christian-inspired group founded in China in the 1990s.
据该团体的教典称 基督已经回归
According to the group, Christ is returned,
但祂以一位中国女性的形式出现 而他们的追随者必须接受他们的教义
but in the form of a Chinese woman, and their followers must embrace your teachings.
政府将其列为邪教
And the government labels this as an evil cult.
关键是 这个教派早就不是第一次出来跳了
And the thing is, this cult isn't even new to controversy.
多年来 当局指控“全能神”犯有强制改宗、财务剥削、家庭暴力和骚扰等罪行
Over the years, authorities have accused Eastern Lightning of forced conversations,
financial exploitation, domestic abuse, and harassment.
据报道 在一些农村地区
In some rural areas, reports say they apply high-pressure tactics on families to join or donate.
他们对家庭施加高压策略 要求他们加入或捐款
对于这次麦当劳杀人事件
In the context of the McDonald's killing,
官方声称那六名袭击者来自“全能神”内部的一个奇怪的分支
the official narrative claims that the six attackers came from a dissident or strange subgroup within Eastern Lightning.
他们可能不受教会中央的管理
Maybe not fully under the church's central control.
但他们的行为符合一些更激进的邪教信仰 比如将非信徒视为恶灵
But their actions align with some of the more radical cult beliefs, rejecting non-believers as evil spirits,
要求服从 如要求提供电话号码或联系方式
demanding submission, as in phone numbers or contact,
还有暴力地强制执行他们的教义
and enforcing their doctrine violently.
袭击者接受了审判
And the attackers were put on trial.
录像、证人和供词等都是判死他们的铁证
The footage, the witnesses, and the confessions all made it impossible to deny what happened.
团体中的两人 包括主犯 被判处死刑 并于2015年执行
Two of the group, including the ringleaders,
Senten to death and executed in 2015.
其他人则被判处长期监禁
The others received long prison sentences.
尘埃落定之后 这个案件成为了现代中国最臭名昭著的邪教犯罪
And in the aftermath, the case became one of the most infamous cult crimes in modern China.
它还导致了突袭、大规模逮捕和铁拳
It sparked raids, mass arrests, and a crackdown on the Church of Almighty God.
招远麦当劳命案至今仍是一个沉痛的警示
The Xiaoyan McDonald's murder remains a disturbing reminder
它向我们展示了信仰是如何走向狂热
of how belief, worked into fanaticism,
并最终在最寻常不过的地方演变为骇人的暴力的
and erupted into violence, in the most ordinary places.
在这个案件中 监控捕捉到的不仅仅是图像
It's a case where surveillance didn't just capture an image.
它捕捉到的是一个意识形态 是一个模糊了信仰和妄想界限的信仰体系
It captured an entire ideology, a belief system that blurred the line between faith and delusion.
它还向世界展示了当一个团体认为自己的谋杀实为救赎时的恐怖
And it showed the world of how truly terrifying it is when a group convinces themselves that killing isn't murder, as salvation.
On the Chinese internet, scandals come and go.
在中国的网络世界里，丑闻此起彼伏
But few have ever reached the scale, or the strangeness, of Sister Hong.
但鲜有事件能和红姐一样出名与诡异
A figure who looked like a woman, who spoke like one.
他打扮成女人，言行举止也在模仿女人
Who lured in hundreds of men.
诱骗了n名男性
But behind the wig, and the mask, wasn't a sister at all.
在假发和伪装背后，他根本不是什么“姐”
It was a man.
就是一男的
A man who spent years recording, deceiving,
一个花费数年时间，通过偷拍、欺骗
and profiting off a secret empire of private videos.
贩卖私密视频建立起地下帝国的男人
And the story is how one disguised figure, full thousands, destroyed lives.
这是一个男人欺骗无数男人，让他们身败名裂的故事
And left behind a digital scar so disturbing,
红姐在中国互联网留下了不可磨灭的印记
the Chinese press called it the viral event of the year.
被中国媒体评为「年度最轰动网络事件」
The story begins with an online profile.
事件起源于一个账号的简介页
A woman, caked in white makeup.
一个满脸厚厚白粉的“女人”
Thick red lipstick.
死亡大红唇
Sometimes even hiding behind a surgical mask.
有时候戴个蓝口罩把脸遮住
She called herself, Sister Hong.
以「红姐」自称
And at first glance, nothing about her profile screamed danger.
乍一看，她的账号挺无害的
She was just another face on dating apps and chat groups.
这在约会软件和群聊里很常见
But Hong's appeal didn't lie in beauty.
但红姐的吸引力并不在于外貌
It laid in curiosity.
而是一种神秘感
Her look was unsettling.
她长得十分惊悚
Almost uncanny.
甚至有几分诡异
And yet, men still messaged her.
就这样，还是会有男的私信她
Many even agreed to meet.
主动约她见面
When they arrived, they found rules.
见面以后，会发现有点不对劲
Strange ones.
红姐的要求不走寻常路
She didn't accept cash for her services.
她不收现金
Instead, men were told to bring items.
带东西来即可
A watermelon. A basket of vegetables.
比如西瓜、果篮
Sometimes even half-used cooking oil.
甚至用过的油都来了
And it wasn't random.
这并非随意的要求
It was actually a cover.
实则是刻意设下的掩护
By avoiding financial transactions, Sister Hong left no paper trail.
不用金钱交易，就不存在经济往来
No receipts.
没有收据
No bank transfers.
没有转账记录
And nothing to tie her encounters to the law.
也就无法用法律界定她的行为
But the strangest rule of all was the lights.
最诡异的一条规矩是
The men weren't allowed to switch them off.
红姐不让这些男的关灯
And whenever someone tried, Sister Hong would calmly get up and flick them back on.
就算你把灯关上，红姐也会若无其事的把灯打开
And they didn't know why, but she did.
这些男的还被蒙在鼓里，而红姐心里一清二楚
Because every moment was actively being recorded.
因为红姐在实时录制他们的行为
Behind those bright lights, hidden cameras were installed around the apartment.
在明亮的灯光下，公寓的各个角落都藏着摄像头
Men came and went, unaware of their faces, their bodies,
男人们来来去去，殊不知脸和金箔被拍的一清二楚
and their secrets were being preserved on hard drives.
然后存进红姐的硬盘里
And for years, nothing leaked.
很多年来，这些视频都没有流出
Sister Hong operated quietly.
红姐一直在暗中活动
Clips were distributed in close groups.
这些视频只发给小圈子的观众
Sometimes on Telegram.
有部分发在电报
Sometimes sold directly to paying subscribers.
或是发给订阅付费用户
$20 a month for access.
一月20刀
Private chats buzzing with new uploads.
私联小群中不断有人议论最新视频
The demand was huge.
而且有很多人要
And so were the numbers.
视频也就越拍越多
By mid-2025, Hong had allegedly recorded encounters with well over a thousand men.
到2025年年中，据称红姐已录下与一千多名男子的“互动”
Some came back repeatedly.
其中一些还是回头客
And one man was nicknamed Four Seasons Brother.
就比如说「四季哥」
Because he returned once per season.
他一个季度来一次
The entire operation was a hidden world.
本来红姐的视频只在小范围内传播
Until one subscriber broke the silence.
直到一个付费用户泄了密
And one day, almost the entire archive was leaked.
在某一天把几乎所有视频都泄了出去
Hundreds of hours of uncensored footage.
几百小时的无码录像
Faces clearly visible.
人脸清晰可辨
And within days, it spread across Chinese social media like a wildfire.
短短几天内，就在中国社交媒体上疯狂扩散
The reaction was explosive.
引起舆论哗然
Suddenly, coworkers, friends, and even family members recognized the men in the videos.
这些男人的同事、亲朋好友都认出了他们
Husbands were caught cheating.
有人是有妇之夫
Boyfriends were exposed.
或是有女友
And one TikToker, with over a million followers,
甚至有一个抖音百万粉网红
was unmasked when viewers noticed his eyebrows matched perfectly with the man in the footage.
观众通过眉毛认出了他，一毛一样
Another was outed to his fiancee.
还有一个人的未婚妻看到了视频
Their engagement was instantly called off.
这婚是结不成了
And the fallout was completely merciless.
这件事造成的结果很残酷
Lives were ended overnight.
无数人的生活一夜崩塌
And the internet wasn't forgiving.
而网友们也没说啥好话
Some viewers mocked the victims.
有人嘲笑受害者
Others turned them into memes.
也有人把他们p成梗图
And as their humiliation spread, so too did the legend of Sister Hong.
随着这些丑事在网上传播，红姐也就成了SSR人物
By July 2025, the scandal wasn't just trending.
到7月，红姐不只是“热搜”这么简单
It was everywhere.
已经无孔不入
The hashtag, TopChinesePlatforms.
#TopChinesePlatforms
Teemed spread internationally.
传到了国外
People dressed up as Sister Hong, wearing wigs and masks.
人们开始模仿红姐的妆造
Dancing in TikTok parodies.
在抖音模仿、恶搞她
And even brands tried to cash in.
甚至有品牌蹭红姐热度
And for many, it became a bizarre, collective joke.
很多人把它当成了一场荒诞的玩笑取乐
But for the men exposed, hundreds of them, it was no joke at all.
那些男的可笑不出来
Their privacy was completely gone.
自己的隐私全没了
Their reputations were ruined.
身败名裂
And what made it worse was the revelation of who Sister Hong really was.
当红姐的真实身份曝光，这件事更显难蚌本色
Because Sister Hong was no woman.
因为红姐压根就不是女的
Beneath the wig and makeup was Jiao, a 38-year-old man from another province.
真实身份为一名38岁的非江苏籍焦姓男子
And for years, he kept his disguise intact.
多年来，他的伪装天衣无缝
But the videos revealed subtle hints.
但从录像还是能看出来几分端倪
Stiff body language.
他的动作十分僵硬
Strange movements.
举止怪诞
A voice that sometimes slipped.
有的时候会夹不住嗓子
And the illusion...
最终，他的伪装
Cracked.
崩塌了
Speculation ran wild.
甚至有谣言说
Was he actually this old?
他其实比38岁大
Was he hiding a disguise?
还有别的马甲
Or was the disguise just a cover for something more sinister?
或者说，红姐这个马甲就是用来掩盖那一层身份的？
And by now, rumors overshadowed reality.
此时，传言早已淹没了事实
But police were about to settle the question.
真相要交给警方揭露
On July 6th, 2025.
2025年7月6日
Nanjing Nianjing police announced the arrest.
南京警方宣布逮捕嫌疑人
The suspect was confirmed.
正式确认了红姐的身份
A 38-year-old man named Jiao.
38岁焦性男子
He was charged with secretly filming and distributing obscene content.
罪名是偷拍「传播淫秽物品」
But by then, the internet had already mythologized him as...
但在那之前，网络上早已把他神化成另一个人物
Red Uncle.
红大爷
Some swore he infected men with HIV.
有人说他把HIV传给了那些男的
Although police stressed the claims were exaggerated.
但是警方说，该说法与事实严重不符
And others clung to the viral number.
有人传的数字很夸张
1,691 men.
共有1691名男子
Officials suggested the rail count was far lower.
警方表示实际数字远低于此
But the damage was already done.
再解释也没用了
In the public image, Sister Hong had already become a monster of legend.
在公众眼中，红姐早已变成了一个传说中的怪物
But after the arrest, police actually revealed another disturbing possibility.
但在他被捕后，警方披露了另一种令人不安的可能
After the rumors spread, it came out that Sister Hong might have actually been HIV positive.
有小道消息称，红姐可能感染了HIV病毒
And if true, the consequences would be catastrophic.
如果这是真的，后果将不堪设想
And for many, most people's life were completely ruined.
红姐视频里很多男的，其实已经社死了
And the tragedy was that many of these men never knew they were being recorded.
最悲哀的是，许多男的从头到尾都被蒙在鼓里
That they had been lured in by deception.
他们也是上了红姐的当
Only to have their faces plastered across the internet for millions to gawk at.
却被无数网民拿来做表情包
But as we all know, the internet moves fast.
但众所周知，网络梗的寿命很短
And within weeks, the memes slowed down.
几周后，红姐相关梗的热度就下去了
New scandals replaced Sister Hong in the trending feed.
新的丑闻接连出现，把红姐挤出热搜
But for the victims, the consequences remained permanent.
然而对受害者来说，他们遭受的伤害永远无法治愈
Their faces, once anonymous, are still floating online.
原本匿名的面孔，如今依然在网上传播
And for some, the looming possibility of infection is a shadow they can't escape.
甚至是部分人一辈子都摆脱不了的噩梦
And as for Jiao, the man who was behind the makeup, wigs and mask.
但是隐藏在浓妆、假发、口罩背后的焦某
His story is still unfinished.
他的故事仍未结束
He could spend the rest of his life behind bars.
他可能将在牢狱中度过余生
Or even worse.
甚至更糟
And in the end, the Sister Hong saga isn't just about deception or scandal.
归根结底，红姐事件不仅仅是一个关于欺骗或丑闻的故事
A reminder of how quickly the internet can transform tragedy into entertainment.
它提醒我们，互联网拿悲剧当乐子的速度有多快
And how, once it does, there's no way back.
一旦娱乐化，就再也回不去了
直播
Livestreams.
它本应是被用来连接起我们的 窥探他人生活的窗口
Are supposed to connect us. They're windows into someone's life.
被用于带来欢笑 集思广益和寻欢作乐
Meant for laughter. Advice. And entertainment.
但就在2021年秋的中国
But in China. In the fall of 2021.
有一场直播并没有将人们连接起来 而是将其困住
One broadcast. Didn't connect. It trapped.
那是一场观众成为了参与者的直播
A livestream. Where viewers became participants.
悲剧便在其中实时上演
And tragedy unfolded. In real time.
罗小猫猫子 一位23岁的时尚网红
Lu Xiaomiao Miaozhi. A 23-year-old fashion influencer.
在抖音（中国版TikTok）上拥有超过60万粉丝
With over 600,000 followers. On Douyin. China's version of TikTok.
她在观众面前活泼爱笑且十分俏皮
And to her audience. She was upbeat, smiling, playful people.
但在镜头之外 她正与严重的抑郁症作斗争
But off screen. She was fighting severe depression.
那年早些时候 她曾住院两个多月
She had been hospitalized for more than two months earlier that year.
用她自己的话说 就是
And in her own words:
"那你们看到我开心的样子 其实都是为了给你们看到啊"
I appear to be happy. But this is all for show.
"我希望大家看到我的视频是开心的 是快乐的"
I hope everyone. Will be happy. When they see my videos.
"是知道我也是快乐的"
And will see that I am happy too.
"可是最近我真的绷不住了"
But, I cannot hold on anymore.
在她最后一次直播前几小时
Hours before her final stream.
她发布了一条名为"大概是最后一条了吧"的视频
She posted a video calling it: Probably my last.
并感谢了粉丝们的陪伴
And thanked her fans for their company.
2021年10月14日
On October 14th, 2021.
罗小猫猫子开播了 她拿着一个瓶子
Lu went live. She held a bottle.
里面混着农药和饮料
Mixed with pesticide and a drink.
一些观众劝她停下来 但另一些人却恰恰相反
Some viewers urged her to stop. But others did the exact opposite.
用诸如"搞快点" "瓶子里不会是尿吧" "要喝快喝"之类的弹幕怂恿她
Egging her on with comments like. Drink it quickly. There is no urine in the bottle. Do it if you are going to do it.
然后她就在直播中喝了下去
And, she swallowed it, on stream.
即使有弹幕刷屏
And even as the chat scrolled.
她自己也在下播后叫了救护车
She herself, called the ambulance after ending the broadcast.
医生试图抢救她 但为时已晚
Doctors tried to save her. But it was already too late.
她的家人表示是直播间里的喷子将她逼到了绝境
Her family said the trolls in the chat. Pushed her over the edge.
其他人则猜测这与她同前任分手有关
Others speculated it was connected to her breakup with an ex.
但她家人坚称这不是原因所在
But her relatives insisted that this wasn't the reason.
她的一位朋友说 罗小猫猫子本不打算结束自己的生命
One friend claimed that Lu did not intend to end her life.
那是一场作秀
That it was an act.
是为了引起她前男友注意而上演的
That was staged to get her ex-boyfriend's attention.
但一旦有评论开始鼓励她 她就真的照做了
But once the comments encouraged her. She went through with it.
截图在网上疯传
The screenshots went viral.
有一个手握毒药的年轻女子
A young woman, holding poison.
而陌生人们却打出侮辱和挑衅的文字
While strangers, type insults and dares.
这场风波堪称完美 它是脆弱与残忍的交汇
It's a perfect storm. For vulnerability and cruelty.
观众的嘲弄将她的痛苦化为笑料
The audience's jeering. Turned her pain into entertainment.
而就在在罗小猫猫子的遗体在山东火化后
And, after Lu's cremation at Shandong.
这场悲剧出现了更黑暗的转折——她的骨灰被盗了
Her tragedy took an even darker turn. Her ashes were stolen.
一名殡仪馆工作人员 一名灵车司机 和一名当地的殡葬师
A funeral home worker. A heurist driver. And a local undertaker.
共同组成了警方后来所称为的"骨灰供应链"
Formed what police later called. A bone ash supply chain.
他们调换了她的骨灰
They swapped her remains.
并试图将其出售供一种民俗所用
And tried to sell them. into an underground practice.
这种习俗仍然盛行于中国的部分地区 即"冥婚"
Still thriving in parts of China. Which is called a ghost marriage.
冥婚可以追溯到商代
Ghost marriages date back to the Shang dynasty.
其所寄托的东西很朴素 却非常令人不安
And the belief is pretty simple. But very disturbing.
那就是"一个未婚的灵魂是不得安宁的"
An unmarried soul is restless.
一个年轻男子独自下葬
A young man. Buried alone.
则可能会给他的家庭带来不幸
Could bring misfortune to his family.
而为了解决这个问题
And to fix this,
亲属会安排一场与年轻女子的遗体甚至只是骨灰的婚事
relatives arrange a marriage with the body. Or even just the ashes of a young woman.
一场有陌生人在其中怂恿的直播
A livestream. Where strangers urged her on.
和一场骨灰被为了牟利而盗走的丧事
A cremation. Where her ashes were stolen for profit.
无论是生是死 罗小猫猫子都被消费了
In life.And in death.Lu was consumed.
这就是为什么她的故事成了中国互联网上最黑暗的悲剧之一
And that's what makes her story. One of the most darkest tragedies.On the Chinese internet.